<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jan Ferme&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jan Ferme&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 - How to start (ASN, BGP, Wireguard tunnel,...)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-27-ipv6-asn-bgp-wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-27-ipv6-asn-bgp-wireguard/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing for the last 15 years that IPv6 is the future. Is it though? Google tracks it and it seems we came a long way since pre-2010 and we&amp;rsquo;re currently sitting at 45%. Not bad, not great.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running pfsense for the last 4 years and at the beginning of the year I decided it was time to finally set it up on the home network. I looked at my options and remembered that my ISP could allocate me an IPv6 range.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD 7.5 router with VLANs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-14-openbsd-7-5-router-with-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-14-openbsd-7-5-router-with-vlans/</guid>
      <description>I run pfSense on my router but the company behind it has started being very anti-community and almost stopped supporting their CE version. So I faced a dilemma. Migrate to OpnSense, VyOS, or something else? I heard many good things about OpenBSD so I thought to myself &amp;ldquo;Why not&amp;rdquo;? I especially like OpenBSD&amp;rsquo;s commitment to high security standards and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what&amp;rsquo;s needed for a router and a firewall that protects your home network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginning of a homelab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-12-31-beginning-of-a-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-12-31-beginning-of-a-homelab/</guid>
      <description>It all started when my friend E. introduced me to the subreddit Homelab. Coincidentally this was on the 1st of April when we&amp;rsquo;re quite hopeful that the whole 2020 situation will go away soon. I started reading all the subreddit&amp;rsquo;s posts and was hooked.&#xA;The main reason to build a homelab was to replace my weak Synology 216play and to extend my storage, my computing power, and learn more about hypervisors, container systems, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why it is so important to back up your data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-1-1-why-it-is-so-important-to-back-up-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-1-1-why-it-is-so-important-to-back-up-your-data/</guid>
      <description>During the four years I worked as a repair technician for iPhones and MacBooks, I heard lots of apologies and stories from people who brought their completely destroyed iPhones for repair on how they accidentally damaged the device.&#xA;Initially, I thought they were apologizing to me but I later realized that they were not apologizing to me but to themselves. About 90% of clients I asked about backing up their iPhone indicated that they never backed up their device in recent months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my new blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-9-6-welcome-to-my-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-9-6-welcome-to-my-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been five years since I wrote something with more than 140 characters. Looking back on things I actually missed it. There was a time where everything was too much and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to write anything. That time has passed.&#xA;What will I write here? Mostly my thoughts and probably more tutorials for different devices that I own. In the upcoming weeks expect:&#xA;Importance of backups Xpenology guide: How to setup it on DSM 6.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
